KRISTA SIMMONS

•San Diego, CA 92104 •(805) 794-4737 •kristasimmons.design@gmail.com

• linkedin.com/in/krista-simmons • www.kristasimmons.io

ABOUT ME

A front-end developer & ux/ui designer from Southern California. Passionate about learning new technologies, implementing and developing great user experience using JavaScript, HTML and CSS. Works well under time constraints and extremely self motivated. A very efficient Googler as well.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS

Technical:

- ❖ Primary Languages: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, PHP, Ruby
- ❖ Knowledgeable: Git Version Control, SQL, PostgreSQL, Sass, RSpec, Ruby on Rails Tools:
 - Atom, Github, Sketch, Wordpress, Shopify, Balsamiq, Photoshop, InVision, Mail-Chimp, Hootsuite

Additional:

- ❖ Search Engine Optimization (SEO) & Google Analytics
- Wireframing & Prototyping
- Agile Methodologies
- User Experience

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Organic SEO

July 2017- April 2018

San Diego, CA

Jr. Full Stack Web Developer

- ❖ Designed and developed a Shopify store for a beverage accessory company
- * Rapid prototyping of email templates and converted designs into HTML
- ❖ Creating custom Wordpress theme from Roots/Sage. Includes prototype design in Sketch, responsive layout and styling, adding site content and configuring plugins
- ❖ SEO implementation to existing Wordpress site
- ❖ iOS app design for nonprofit volunteer app

KSIMMONS DEVELOPMENT

March 2017- July 2017

Freelance Web Developer & Designer

San Diego, CA

- Designed and developed a Shopify store for a beverage accessory company
- * Rapid prototyping of email templates and converted designs into HTML
- ❖ Creating custom Wordpress theme from Roots/Sage. Includes prototype design in Sketch, responsive layout and styling, adding site content and configuring plugins
- ❖ SEO implementation to existing Wordpress site
- ❖ iOS app design for nonprofit volunteer app

SCIENTIST.COM

February 2017-March 2017

Full-Stack Web Development Intern

San Diego, CA

- Implementing a shipment/tracking API for both the customer and supplier portion of the web app
- Utilizing HTML, JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap for the front-end, and Ruby and CouchDB for the back-end
- Created web design wireframes/mockups using Sketch
- * Responsible for testing the features and it's responsiveness across all browsers and devices

SPECIALIST STAFFING SOLUTIONS

January 2015-October 2016

Technical Recruiter

San Diego, CA

- ❖ Involved in the full-cycle recruiting process for IT positions, from business development to sourcing candidates for open positions
- ❖ Extend, negotiate and close offers with both clients and candidates
- Write compelling job descriptions, interview guidelines, tailored and personalized Inmails
- Track, manage and analyze data through Salesforce CRM

KELLER WILLIAMS REALTY

Social Media & Marketina Coordinator

February 2014-August 2014

San Diego, CA

- ❖ Prepared listing researches on the MLS databases for the Luxury Real Estate Division
- ❖ Managed and implemented social media accounts for 2 realtors, including Facebook, Twitter, Yelp, Google Plus and YouTube as well as creating a Wordpress blog
- Generated leads through phone prospecting and marketing tools such as Market Leader

EDUCATION

LEARN ACADEMY

November 2016- February 2017

Full-Time immersive Web Development Boot camp

San Diego, CA

SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY

May 2015

College of Business Administration, Bachelor of Science, Marketing

San Diego, CA

INTERESTS

- Blogging
- Event Planning

- Music Production
- User Experience